Guide to the Katherine S. Dreier Papers / Societe Anonyme Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Société Anonyme: Subject Files about Artists, 1872-1952; Series X; 9.2; (24 boxes)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1949, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2407)
  - Bortnyik, Sándor, 1949, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2408)
  - Bragaglia, Leonardo, 1924-25, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2409-2410)
  - Brancusi, Constantin, 1926, 1950, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2411-2413)
  - Braque, Georges, 1943, 1949, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2414-2416)
  - Bromberger, Dora, 1949, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2417)
  - Brown, Douglas Edwin, 1938-47, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2418)
  - Bruce, Patrick Henry, 1938, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2419)
  - Buchheister, Carl, 1949, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2420-2423)
  - Burliuk, David, 1926-51, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 2424-2434)
  - Cahn, Marcelle, 1926, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 2435)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1929-49, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 2436-2437)
  - Campendonk, Heinrich, 1920-49, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 2438-2444)
  - Carlsund, Otto G., 1926-50, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 2445-2447)
  - Carra, Carlo, 1926, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2448)
  - Carroll, Leon, 1930-40, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2449-2451)
  - Cézanne, Paul, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2452)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2453-2455)
  - Charchoune, Serge, 1926, 1949, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2456)
  - Cickowsky, N., 1926, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2457)
  - Clausen, Franciska, 1926, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2458)
  - Constable, John, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2459)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2850
  - Coogler, Mary A., 1939, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2460)
  - Coulter, Sheilagh Maeve, 1950 (Box 99, Folder 2461)
  - Covert, John R., 1945, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2462)
    Contains 3 copy prints.
  - Crotti, Jean, 1927-49, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2463-2465)
  - Csaky, Joseph, 1943, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2466)
  - Dalí, Salvador, n.d.
    See: Oversize, box 120, folder 2851
  - Daugherty, James Henry, 1949, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2467)
  - Davis, Stuart, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2468)
  - De Chirico, Giorgio, 1925-47, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2469-2470)
  - Demuth, Charles, 1926, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2471)
  - Depero, Fortunato, 1929, 1949, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2472)
  - Derain, André, 1949, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2473)
  - Detwiller, Frederick K., 1920-35 (Box 100, Folder 2474)
  - Dickinson, Preston, 1926, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2475)
  - Diller, Burgoyne, 1949, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2476)
  - Doesburg, Alexander van, 1923-49, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2477-2478)
  - Domela, 1926, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2479)
  - Donas, Marthe, 1949, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2480)
  - Dottori, Gerardo, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2481)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2852
  - Dove, Arthur Garfield, 1947, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2482)
  - Dreier, Dorothea A., 1925-30, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2483-2486)
  - Dreier, Dorothea A. Scrapbook on, 1925-26, n.d.
    See: Oversize, box 130, folder 2874
  - Dreier, Katherine S., 1946, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2487)
  - Drevin, Aleksandr, 1949, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2488)
  - Drewes, Werner, 1936-49, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2489-2491)
  - Dreyer, Friedrich Adolf, 1949, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2492)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, 1919-49, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2493-2497)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2853
  - Duchamp, Suzanne, 1933, 1949, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2498)
  - Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, 1923-43, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2499)
  - Dzubas, Friedel, 1949, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2500)
  - Eilshemius, Louis M., 1924-49, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2501-2503)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2854
  - Eldred, Thomas, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2504)
  - Erbslöh, Adolf, 1949, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2505)
  - Erler, Fritz, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2506)
  - Ernst, Max, 1926-48, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2507-2508)
  - Feininger, Lyonel, 1943-50, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2509-2510)
  - Ferren, John, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2511)
  - Filla, Emil, 1926, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2512)
  - Finnur Jónsson, 1949, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2513)
  - Fischer, Oskar, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2514)
  - Fischinger, Oskar, 1949, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2515)
  - Fitzsimmons, James, 1947-49, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2516)
  - Gabo, Naum, 1923-51, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2517-2519)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2855
  - Garbe, Herbert, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2520)
  - Gargallo, Pablo, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2521)
  - Gauguin, Paul, 1913-49, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2522-2523)
  - Gaulois, Paul, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2524)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2856
  - Glarner, Fritz, 1930-49, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2525)
  - Gleizes, Albert, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2526)
  - Gogh, Vincent van, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2527)
  - Goldthwaite, Anne, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2528)
  - Gorky, Arshile, 1946-50, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2529)
  - Graham, John, 1929-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2530)
  - Granovsky, N., n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2531)
  - Grigoriev, Boris, 1935, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2532)
  - Gris, Juan, 1926-48, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2533-2535)
  - Gropius, Walter, n.d.
    See: Oversize, box 120, folder 2857
  - Gutfreund, Oto, 1926, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2536)
  - Gwozdecki, Gustave de, 1928, 1949, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2537)
  - Haines, Lett, 1926, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2538)
  - Halicka, Alice, 1923-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2539)
  - Hals, Frans, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2540)
  - Harris, Lawren, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2541)
  - Hartley, Marsden, 1922, 1949, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2542)
  - Heemskerk, Jacoba van, 1924-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2543)
  - Hekking, William M., 1931, 1937, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2544)
  - Hildebrandt, Lily, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 2545-2547)
  - Hoerle, Angelika, 1949, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2548)
  - Hoerle, Heinrich, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2549)
  - Holtzman, Harry, 1942, 1949, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2550)
  - Huszár, Vilmos, 1926, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2551)
  - Itten, Johannes, 1926, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2552)
  - Jacobi, Rudolf, 1949, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2553)
  - Jawlensky, Alexej von, 1930-49, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2554)
  - Kádár, Béla, 1924-49, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2555)
  - Kakabaze, Davit, 1926, 1949, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2556-2558)
  - Kaminsky, Dora, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2559)
  - Kamys, Walter, 1948-50, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2560)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1926-50, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2561-2569)
  - Kelpe, Paul, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2570)
  - Kesting, Edmund, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2571)
  - Keyser, Ragnhild, 1926, 1947, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2572)
  - Kiesler, Steffi, 1949, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2573)
  - Klee, Paul, 1931-50, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2574-2577)
  - Klien, Erika Giovanna, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2578)
  - Knaths, Karl, 1926, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2579)
  - Kokoschka, Oskar, 1947 (Box 106, Folder 2580)
  - Kuethe, Adolf, 1926, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2581)
  - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1926, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2582)
  - Léger, Fernand, 1919-50, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2583-2586)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2858
  - Legrain, Pierre, 1930, 1949, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2587)
  - Legrand, Edy, 1946 (Box 106, Folder 2588)
  - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, 1932-51, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2589-2591)
  - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1930-51, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2592-2595)
  - Lipton, Seymour, 1950 (Box 106, Folder 2596)
  - Lissitzky, El, 1924-49, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2597-2598)
  - Lozowick, Louis, 1923-49, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2599)
  - Lubbers, Adriaan, 1925-49, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2600-2602)
  - Malevich, Kazimir Severinovich, 1928-49, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2603-2604)
  - Manet, Edouard, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2605)
  - Marasco, Antonio, 1949, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2606)
  - Marc, Franz, 1916-52, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2607-2610)
  - Marcoussis, Louis, 1941, 1949, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2611)
  - Marin, John, 1923-49, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2612)
  - Mataré, Ewald, 1946-49, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2613-2615)
  - Matisse, Henri, 1915-49, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2616-2619)
  - Matta Echaurren, Roberto Sebastián, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2620)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2859
  - Matulka, Jan, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2621)
  - Medunetsky, Kasimir, 1949, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2622)
  - Mense, Carlo, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2623)
  - Metzinger, Jean, 1943, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2624)
  - Meyer, Georg? [G. M.], 1948-49, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2625)
  - Michel, Robert, 1949, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2626)
  - Miro, Joan, 1925-49, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2627)
  - Moholy-Nagy, László, 1926-46, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2628-2630)
  - Moll, Leo Ziemssen, 1930-32, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2631)
  - Molzahn, Johannes, 1919-50, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2632-2637)
  - Mondrian, Piet, 1944-51, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2638-2641)
  - Muche, Georg, 1949, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2642)
  - Müller, Felix, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2643)
  - Münter-Kandinsky, Gabriele, 1925-26, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2644)
  - Nau, Armand, 1926, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2645)
  - Nauen, Heinrich, 1919-49, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2646-2647)
  - Nebel, Otto, 1949, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2648)
  - Nevinson, C. R. W., n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2649)
  - Newby, Ruby Warren, 1940, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2650)
  - Nicolle, Emile, 1949, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2651)
  - Nitzschke, Hans, 1926, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2652)
  - Nolde, Emil, 1916-49, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2653-2654)
  - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1926, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2655)
  - Orozco, José Clemente, 1931-34, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2656)
  - Österblom, Olof, 1926, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2657)
  - Outerbridge, Paul, 1949, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2658)
  - Pach, Walter, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2659)
  - Paladini, Vinicio, 1923, 1926, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2660)
  - Pannaggi, Ivo, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2661-2663)
  - Papazoff, Georges, 1931-50, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2664)
  - Pechstein, Max, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2665)
  - Peri, Laszlo, 1949, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2666)
  - Pevsner, Antoine, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2667-2668)
  - Phillips, Holmead, 1927-49, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2669)
  - Phillips, Marjorie, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2670)
  - Phocas, Suzanne, 1926, 1949, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2671)
  - Picabia, Francis, 1918-50, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2672-2674)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1913-51, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2675-2677)
  - Piper, John, 1948 (Box 111, Folder 2678)
  - Post, Hermann, 1922-49, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2679)
  - Pougny, Jean, 1949, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2680)
  - Prampolini, Enrico, 1923, 1949, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2681)
  - Putnam, Wallace, 1935-49, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2682-2685)
  - Räderscheidt, Anton, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2686)
  - Ray, Man, 1919-49, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2687-2690)
  - Redon, Odile, 1913-49, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2691)
  - Reid, Robert, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2692)
  - Rembrandt, Harmenszoon van Rijn (Box 112, Folder 2693)
  - Ribemont-Dessaignes, Georges, 1949, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2694)
  - Richter, Hans, 1948-50, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2695)
  - Roche, Juliette, 1920 (Box 112, Folder 2696)
  - Rosenborg, Ralph M., n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2697)
  - Sala, Raphael, 1949, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2698)
  - Schamberg, Morton Livingston, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2699)
  - Schanker, Louis, 1945 (Box 112, Folder 2700)
  - Scheiber, Hugo, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2701)
  - Schlemmer, Oskar, 1950 (Box 112, Folder 2702)
  - Schmidt-Rottluff, Karl, 1920-49, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2703-2704)
  - Schrimpf, Georg, 1920-49, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2705)
  - Schwichtenberg, Martel, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2706)
  - Schwitters, Kurt, 1922-48, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2707-2713)
  - Seiwert, Franz Wilhelm, 1949, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2714)
  - Servranckx, Victor, 1926-47, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2715-2716)
  - Severini, Gino, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2717)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2860
  - Shirlaw, Walter, 1930, 1949, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2718)
  - Shirlaw, Walter. Scrapbook on, 1910-30, n.d.
    See: Oversize, box 132, folder 2875
  - Shirlaw, Walter. Loose material from scrapbook on, 1910, 1930, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 2719)
  - Shwab, Walmar, 1949, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2720)
  - Smith, David, 1940 (Box 114, Folder 2721)
  - Solotaroff, M., n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2722)
  - Spencer, Niles, 1926, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2723)
  - Steger, Milly, 1949-50, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2724)
  - Steichen, Edward, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2725)
  - Steinberg, Bruno, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2726)
  - Steinitz, Kate Traumann, 1949, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2727)
  - Stella, Joseph, 1918-49, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2728-2736)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2861
  - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1926 (Box 114, Folder 2737)
  - Storm Petersen, Robert, 1926, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2738)
  - Storrs, John Henry Bradley, 1920-49, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2739-2741)
  - Stuckenberg, Fritz, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2742)
  - Survage, Léopold, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2743)
  - Taeuber-Arp, Sophie, 1949, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2744-2745)
  - Taut, Bruno, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2746)
  - Topp, Arnold, 1949, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2747)
  - Torres-García, Joaquín, 1921, 1949, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2748)
  - Udaltzova, Nadezhda Andreevina, 1949, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2749)
  - Uhden, Maria, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2750)
  - Valmier, Georges, 1949, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2751)
  - Van Everen, Jay, 1926, 1949, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2752-2753)
  - Vantongerloo, Georges, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2754)
  - Vasilieff, Nicholas, 1929-49, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2755-2757)
  - Villon, Jacques, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2758-2763)
    Contains 2 copy prints.
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2862
  - Vogeler, Johann Heinrich, 1921, 1949, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2764-2765)
  - Vordemberge-Gildewart, Friedrich, 1926, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2766)
  - Wahlstedt, Walther, 1949, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2767)
  - Walden, Herwarth, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2768)
  - Walkowitz, Abraham, 1928-46, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2769-2772)
  - Weber, Max, 1923-49, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2773)
  - Whistler, James McNeill. Scrapbook on, 1872-1904, n.d.
    See: Oversize, box 132, folder 2876
  - Whistler, James McNeill. Loose material from scrapbook on, 1895-1908, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2774-2780)
  - Williamson-Kent, William, 1950 (Box 117, Folder 2781)
  - Wood, Grant, 1935 (Box 117, Folder 2782)
  - Zak, Eugene, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2783)
  - Zamoyski, August, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2784)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2863
  - Zeller, Magnus, 1949, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2785)
  - Zorach, Marguerite, 1926, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2786)
  - Zorach, William, 1923, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2787)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2788-2790)
    See also: Oversize, box 120, folder 2864
- Katharine S. Dreier Papers Addition, 1895-1953; Series XI; 6.8; (14 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized chronologically by accession.
  Series XI. Katherine S. Dreier Papers Addition contains correspondence, photographs, printed material, artwork and other papers by or relating to Katherine Dreier.
  This series received a basic level of processing. Various acquisitions associated with the addition have not been merged and organized as a whole. Each acquisition is described separately in the contents list below according to month and year of acquisition. Folder titles appearing in the contents list below are often based on those provided by the creator or previous custodian. Titles have not been verified against the contents of the folders in all cases. Otherwise, folder titles are supplied by staff during initial processing.
  Former call numbers: Uncat MSS 916, Uncat MSS 952, and Uncat MSS 1058.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Theodore Dreier, 2006-2007, and Theodore and Barbara Dreier, 2008.
  - November 2006 Acquisition
    - German letters, circa 1940-1950; 12 (Box 145)
    - KSD letters to family other miscellaneous, 1895-1950; 2 (Box 145)
    - MED letters to KSD from London, 1911, 2 (Box 145)
    - Villon correspondence, 1947-1949; 3 (Box 145)
    - Miscellaneous letters and documents to or about KSD, 1913-1948 (Box 145)
    - KSD letters, 1948-1949 (Box 145)
    - KSD correspondence, 1927-1937 (Box 145)
    - KSD writings, 1917, undated; 3 (Box 145)
    - Photos of KSD's home in Milford, CT, 1947, undated; 2 (Box 145)
    - Housewarming, West Redding, 1931 October 31 (Box 145)
    - KSD in print/news, 1930-1947 (Box 145)
    - Shows, catalogs, reviews, 1912-1943; 2 (Box 145)
    - KSD lectures at Yale, 1920, 1948 (Box 145)
    - Societe Anonyme show at Yale in memory of KSD, 1941-1953 (Box 145)
    - Societe Anonyme and Yale, 1920-1952, undated; 3 (Box 145)
    - Girl With a Blue Bowl and other works by KSD, undated; 3 (Box 145)
    - Asian-inspired print, undated (Box 145)
    - Travel, finances, 1911-1929; 2 (Box 145)
    - Charitable, 1919-1924 (Box 145)
    - Loans, gifts, bequests, 1941-1952 (Box 145)
    - Obituaries, 1928, 1952 (Box 145)
    - Catalog: Katherine S. Dreier, Academy of Allied Arts, 1933 (Box 145)
    - Woman Suffrage papers, 1915-1916; 2 (Box 146)
    - Journal, 1891-1918, undated; 5 (Box 146)
    - Photo album, 1924-1939; 2 (Box 146)
    - Sketchbook, 1913-1919 (Box 146)
    - Photo negatives, undated (Box 146)
    - Collection of the Societe Anonyme, 1950; 3 (Box 146)
    - "Duchamp's glass", 1944 May (Box 147)
    - "Collection of the Societe Anonyme", MOMA 1920 (Box 147)
    - Charles Seymoure correspondence, 1941 October; 2 (Box 147)
    - Photographs and related papers, undated; 8 (Box 147)
    - Collages, undated (Box 147)
    - Art News Magazine, 1953 January (Box 147)
    - Minutes of the German Committee of USA, 1914-1915 (Box 147)
    - Notes and impressions on my trip to South America, 1918-1919 (Box 147)
    - Correspondence, notes, 1932-1934 (Box 147)
    - Guestbook, 1924-1952; 2 (Box 147)
    - Pamphlet re: Ginling College, 1919 (Box 147)
    - Edward & Ethel Dreier's guest book, 1904-1908 (Box 147)
    - Illustrated notecard book (possibly by Marion Litchfield), undated (Box 147)
    - Photo album, 1905-1924, undated; 3 (Box 148)
    - Photos of KSD, 1888-1949, undated; 3 (Box 148)
    - Photographs of KSD's art, 1909-1912 (Box 148)
    - Guest book, circa 1931 (Box 148)
    - Engagement calendars, 1919-1950; 16 (Box 148)
    - Address books, 1926, undated (Box 148)
    - Trip to Europe (journal), 1891 July (Box 149)
    - Diary, 1893-1897 (Box 149)
    - Poetry journal, 1892-1898 (Box 149)
    - Scrapbook, 1895-1898 (Box 149)
    - Trips to Europe (journal), 1902-1903 (Box 149)
    - Memory book, trip abroad (scrapbook), 1902-1903 (Box 149)
    - Notes on lectures by Herr Bridock, Munich, 1911-1912 (Box 149)
  - Oversize
    - Photo album, 1913-1918; 2 (Box 150)
    - 40 variations (parts i and ii), 1937; 2 (Box 150)
    - Ledger, 1934 (Box 151)
    - Trip to China (diary), 1922 (Box 151)
    - Reproductions of art work, undated (Box 151)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 151)
    - Photo album, "The haven", undated (Box 152)
    - Photos of trip to China, 1922 (Box 152)
    - Photo album, trip to Europe, 1896 (Box 153)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 154)
    - Scrapbook, 1905-1920 (Box 154)
    - Correspondence to KSD thanking and congratulating on catalogue, 1950 (Box 155)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 155)
  - June 2007 Acquisition
    - Correspondence, 1908-1921 (Box 156)
    - KSD letters to MED, 1929-1931 (Box 156)
    - Correspondence from Willa Cather, undated (Box 156)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 156)
    - Checkbook, 1919 (Box 156)
    - Notes on the mind and body, 1911, 1920 (Box 156)
    - Diary, 1918-1920 (Box 156)
    - Loose pages from photgraph album, 1924, undated (Box 156)
    - Empty envelopes, 2001-2006 (Box 156)
    - German home; glass plates and film, undated (Box 157)
  - November 2008 Acquisition
    - Photo album, 1924-1927 (Box 158)
- Oversize, 23.2; (16 boxes)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series I-X, arranged in box order.
  - Alajalov, Constantin. Letters to KSD (in Series I), 1926, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2791)
    Contains 5 letters.
  - Artext Prints, Inc. Poster (in Series I) (Box 118, Folder 2792)
  - Arts Council of the City of New York
    - Poster (in Series I), 1924 (Box 118, Folder 2793)
    - Advertisement (in Series I), n.d.
  - Diller, Burgoyne. Letter to KSD (in Series I), 1946 Jul 31 (Box 118, Folder 2794)
  - Léger, Fernand. Letter to KSD (in Series I), 1928 Jan 26 (Box 118, Folder 2795)
  - Transatlantic Shipping Company. Receipts (5) (in Series I), 1920 Oct 28 (Box 118, Folder 2796)
  - W. F. Collins & Co. Receipts (in Series I) (Box 118, Folder 2797)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. "Modern Art Sesquicentennial" (exhibition catalog). Proofs (in Series II), 1926 (Box 118, Folder 2798)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. 40 Variations. Advertisements, printed (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2799)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. Burliuk. Galley proofs, corrected (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2800-2801)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. Five Months in the Argentine, from a Woman's Point of View, 1918 to 1919. Advertisement (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2802)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. Personal Recollections of Vincent van Gogh by Elisabeth du Quesne van Gogh, translated by KSD. Galley proofs, corrected (incomplete) (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2803)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. Unidentified book. "Books by the Same Author," galley proof, corrected (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2804)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. [Radio talks on art]. Manuscript notes, possibly by Marcel Duchamp (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2805)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. [History of painting], holograph notes (in Series II) (Box 118, Folder 2806)
  - Cheatham, Kitty. "America Acknowledges Spiritual Debt to Sweden, in Honoring Crown Prince Gustaf Adolf and Crown Princess Louise," printed version of radio talk, 1926 May 28 (in Series II) (Box 118, Folder 2807)
  - Duchamp, Marcel. From the Green Box. Advertisement (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2808)
  - Unidentified author. [Love is very patient...], poem, printed version (in Series II), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2809)
  - Cooperative Mural Workshops. Brochure for exhibition at Carroll Galleries, proof of cover (in Series III), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2810)
  - Haven (West Redding, Conn.). Poster for auction at, 1918 Oct 10 (2 copies) (in Series III) (Box 118, Folder 2811)
  - Shawn, Ted. Advertisement for "Shawn and His Ensemble of Men Dancers" (in Series III) (Box 118, Folder 2812)
  - Academy of Allied Arts. Flyer for KSD's exhibition and lectures (in Series IV), 1933 (Box 118, Folder 2813)
  - Invitation and catalog for exhibition "Creative Families in Art" (in Series IV) (Box 118, Folder 2814)
  - George Vietor. Stock dividends (in Series IV), 1904 (Box 118, Folder 2815)
  - New York Life Insurance and Trust Company. Stock dividends (in Series IV), 1900-06 (Box 118, Folder 2816)
  - "Katherine S. Dreier: Lecturer and Painter," brochure. Proofs, corrected in Series IV) (Box 118, Folder 2817)
  - Russian wolfhound pedigree (in Series IV) (Box 118, Folder 2818)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. "Founding of Paterson" (1 print) (in Series V) (Box 118, Folder 2819)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. "Madame Gadeki as Aida" (in Series V), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2820)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. [Man wearing bow tie] (2 prints) (in Series V), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2821)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. "Sketch for a Reredos" (in Series V), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2822)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. [Woman feeding chickens] (in Series V), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2823)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. [Woman reflected in mirror] (in Series V), n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2824)
  - 135 Central Park West (New York, N.Y.). View of Marcel Duchamp's "Tu m'" over bookcases (1 print) (in Series V), [ca. 1918] (Box 119, Folder 2825)
  - Dreier, Katherine S. Studio portrait (in portfolio), with knotted necklace and patterned dress (3 prints) (in Series V) (Box 119, Folder 2826-2828)